A Guide to the Harrison Southworth Scrapbooks 1880-1920
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Harrison Southworth Scrapbooks 1880-1920
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
1575
This collection consists of 10 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restricted due to fragility of collection. Contact Special Collections for more information.
Acquisition Information
This collection was acquired by the University of Virginia December 7, 1942 as a gift.
Biographical/Historical Information
Tappahannock, Va., Republican politician. Southworth was a Confederate soldier, member of the Virginia House of Delegates, 1885-1887, and Essex County, Va. clerk, 1887-.
Scope and Content Information
Southworth compiled scrapbooks of newsclippings pertaining to Virginia and U.S. politics with an emphasis on the career of William Mahone. Other topics include the Confederate legacy, prohibition, and racial and religious issues. Elections tickets are pasted in several volumes.
Contents List
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings: Virginia politics and some national politics 1880-1886, n.d. (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings: Virginia and U.S. politics, prohibition, Confederate remnants 1881-1906, n.d. (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings: Virginia and U.S. politics, election ballots; public affairs; Virginia's debt, schools, Confederate legacy 1884-1893, n.d. (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings: U.S. and Virginia politics, elections, new election law 1895, n.d. (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings: social issues including race, religion, confederate memorabilia, and Virginia party politics 1895-1901, n.d. (Box 2)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings: U.S. and Virginia politics, and social issues including race, prohibition, and Confederate remnants 1903-1904, n.d. (Box 2)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings: legacy of Confederacy, prohibition, race, and Virginia and national politics 1907-1908, n.d. (Box 2)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings: some Virginia and U.S. politics, more on social issues: race, religion and prohibition 1909-1910, n.d. (Box 2)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings: social and religious issues, race, Virginia and U.S. politics 1910-1911, n.d. (Box 2)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings on First World War: Armistice, Peace Conference, Treaty, Wilson's re-election 1918-1920, n.d. (Box 2)